<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Vanessa's Blog</title><link href="https://vanessa-kris.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://vanessa-kris.github.io/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://vanessa-kris.github.io/</id><updated>2022-01-26T01:30:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Job Description</title><link href="https://vanessa-kris.github.io/job-description.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-01-26T01:30:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-01-26T01:30:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Vanessa Christopher</name></author><id>tag:vanessa-kris.github.io,2022-01-26:/job-description.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Think about your audience&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Hi there!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am currently interning with Fedora on the project "Extend and improve NeuroFedora's user consumable artefacts".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is Fedora?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fedora is a Linux operating system. The computers we have at home are similar it has an operating system called windows, Fedora is just another one like Windows just with differnt features. The operating system tells the computer what to do when you move the mouse or press a key on the keyboard. etc . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So just like we have operating systems for phone like iphone and android, we also have different ones for computers like MacOS, Windows, Fedora Linux e.t.c.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now to do anything more with your computer you need to have aplications just like whatsapp and twitter on our phones, on the compter you can have web browser that lets you access youtube, whatsapp e.t.c. The process of adding new applications to your phone or computer is called installing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this internship program I make lots of applications easy to install on the Fedora Linux operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got this internship through Outreachy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is Outreachy?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.outreachy.org/"&gt;Outreachy&lt;/a&gt; is a program that organizes three months paid internsips with free and open source software (see explanation below) projects for people who are typically underrepresented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The program is mainly for women, transgender, gender queer, non-binary people, people of color, and people who face discrimination because of caste or tribe, men who face discrimination in the industry can also apply for the program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Free and open source software&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is both free and open, where anyone is freely licensed to use, copy, study and change the software in any way and the souce code is openly shared that people are encouraged to voluntarily improve the design of the software .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outreachy has vast list of projects to work on but I chose Fedora and I am loving the experience so far, and I am hoping even after the internship I will still be an active contributor to Fedora.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Blog"></category><category term="Outreachy"></category><category term="NeuroFedora"></category></entry><entry><title>Week7 Blog Post</title><link href="https://vanessa-kris.github.io/week7-blog-post.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-01-22T05:30:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-01-22T05:30:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Vanessa Christopher</name></author><id>tag:vanessa-kris.github.io,2022-01-22:/week7-blog-post.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Modifying Expectations&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello there! and welcome once again to my blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is about a journey of adventure, headaches, victory dances and learning!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What was my original internship project timeline?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Week 1-2: Learn the Fedora package maintainer process, and improve existing packages via pull requests to practice the workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Week 3-5: Go over the NeuroFedora packaging queue and identify a list of tools for packaging&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Week 6-9: Follow the Fedora package maintaining process, and submit packages for review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Week 10: Follow the review process and make necessary improvements to submitted packages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Week 12: Submit packages for QA, test them, update documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What have I accomplished in the first half of the internship&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would say being an open source contributor is the biggest achievement so far as this is my first open source project, also i contribute to an organization as big as Fedora. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this first half i've being able to package python spec files,make updates and even review other packages, learn more about git as i practice. Generally i think I and my mentor have already gone over list 😄&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What project goals took longer than expected?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The projects I found most challenging was learning how to write blogs for non technical audience, but my mentor carefully took me through a session where he explained the bits of writing for a non technical audience and i'm sure with more practice i'll get better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also building some packages took longer than expected, but with some help of course i had my victory dance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What would I do differently if I were starting the internship over?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If i was to start my internship over again? well i wouldn't change much because i love my learning curve and speed, though some times it's challenging and i spend more time on projects than expected but my mentor tries to help me out and modify my timing to help me understand better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But... i think i should have started taking notes earlier as i forget alot of little details 😄&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is my new plan for the second half of the internship?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I plan on making notes at every step and also timing myself to catch up with my given tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Outreachy internship has really been awesome, it gave me the opportunity to be part of a bigger community, to learn things i never knew about, to meet awesome people and become a better version of myself. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Blog"></category><category term="Outreachy"></category><category term="NeuroFedora"></category></entry><entry><title>Everybody Struggles</title><link href="https://vanessa-kris.github.io/everybody-struggles.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-12-21T19:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-12-21T19:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Vanessa Christopher</name></author><id>tag:vanessa-kris.github.io,2021-12-21:/everybody-struggles.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Everybody Struggles&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;What am I really doing?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RPM packaging with Fedora. RPM files are like zip files (compressed) composed of different softwares mixed to work together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's just say an RPM packager does the packaging so users can simply use a command line to install softwares e.g &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo dnf install fedora-packager
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before Outreachy I did not have the slightest idea of what packaging was all about as a matter of fact it was completely new to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How it all started&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scrolling through lists of outreachy projects, I came accross the NeuroFedora project and I picked interest in it because it did not require much (lol) ... I joined the Fedora community and jeez I was lost, everything was so new I just wanted to give up, but I saw other applicants curious and asking questions. So I decided to give it a try. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read the docs sent by our mentor (Ankur Sinha) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://fedoramagazine.org/rpm-packages-explained"&gt;RPM Packages explained&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well... I was getting a hang of it but not so much and gosh I was intimidated by how much my collegues were picking up already. I decided to write my mentor (private) and he replied! He led me to the open chat where I mustered up courage to ask questions about my uncertainties and within few weeks I was already packaging for Fedora. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most interesting part is till now I "always" get stuck on projects and still seek help from my mentor and community members.  I've learnt through the journey that no one really knows it all but you can strive for mastery by consistency, openess, and willingness. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Blog"></category><category term="Outreachy"></category><category term="NeuroFedora"></category></entry><entry><title>Introduction</title><link href="https://vanessa-kris.github.io/introduction.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-12-10T19:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-12-10T19:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Vanessa Christopher</name></author><id>tag:vanessa-kris.github.io,2021-12-10:/introduction.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is an introduction of myself&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am Vanessa Christopher (she/her) a Cameroonian, I am 21.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My core values are intelligence, growth and freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;most people really underestimate their brain power, but as for me I believe I can do anything I put my mind to! I wanna know more, explore and grow! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s where growth comes in, I value growth even in the smallest scale as long as you are making progress and not giving up !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And lastly freedom! I believe everyone should be free to practice whatever, go into any field of choice as long as no one is getting hurt!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I heard about outreachy, an internship that welcomes total beginners that was a very good motivation and the stipends?? Free mentoring from professionals? This was definitely my chance to broaden my scope.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Blog"></category><category term="Outreachy"></category><category term="NeuroFedora"></category></entry></feed>